⊸ JOSIAH ENUMAH ∽

FRONT END ENGINEER

CONTACT



+2348084809607, +2348032578022



in linkedin.com/in/josiah-enumah



mailto:josiahenumah94@gmail.com



https://josiahenumah.netlify.app



https://github.com/JosiahENUMAH



23, Alhaji Alimi Street, Off Ilaje Road, Bariga, Lagos State. Nigeria.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced IT professional specialising in the development of visually appealing and interactive web applications. Collaborates with crossfunctional teams to ensure user satisfaction and drive product and revenue growth. Expertise lies in utilising React.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and other innovative technologies to create exceptional digital experiences.

PROJECTS: [Follow GitHub link for more projects.]

- www.stafftribes.com Unfair Advantage: A social application for connecting with people, managing events, etc.
- www.kingcabana.com (In view): Implementing and integrating event organiser, sponsors and vendor user-flows for the company's web app.
- https://theolympiansmall.netlify.app An e-commerce store.

SKILLS

- JAVASCRIPT, HTML & CSS
- **REACT.JS & METEOR.JS**
- SEMANTIC & MATERIAL UI
- **REDUX & STATE MANAGEMENT**
- STYLED COMPONENTS, TAILWIND & **BOOTSTRAP**
- GIT, FIGMA & ATLASSIAN TOOLS
- PRODUCT & GENERAL **MANAGEMENT**
- **COMPUTER ENGINEERING**

WORK HISTORY

Front End Engineer, 03/2023 – Present

Unfair Advantage - Helsinki, Finland

- Utilised Meteor.js to integrate Figma screens and consume APIs for the social application, resulting in a 45% increase in app responsiveness and a 20% faster loading rate.
- Worked closely with stakeholders to ensure stafftribes.com met project requirements, attaining 95% alignment with initial specifications.
- Coordinated extensive product testing, reducing bugs by 30% and upgrading app performance and stability.

Frontend Developer, 11/2022 – Present

King Cabana Limited — Lagos, Nigeria

- Developed features for mobile and desktop platforms, using JavaScript and Version Control tools, enhancing user experience by 35%.
- Deployed techniques for the creation of React reusable components that accelerated MVP launch by 25% and received positive test feedback.
- Cooperated with teams and management to optimise creative proposals and design practices, achieving 98% of Objectives & Key Results.

EDUCATION

Obafemi Awolowo University 2016 - 2020

Bachelor of Science - BSc Engineering Physics

CERTIFICATIONS

- THE WEB DEVELOPER BOOTCAMP UDEMY, UNITED STATES OF AMERICA (USA)
- PRODUCT MANAGEMENT PRINCIPLES -ENTRYLEVEL.NET, AUSTRALIA
- **PROFESSIONAL ETHICS** CORPORATE FINANCE INSTITUTE (CFI), CANADA
- ASSOCIATE PROJECT MANAGEMENT PROFESSIONAL (PMP) - INTERNATIONAL **INSTITUTE OF PROJECT & SAFETY** MANAGEMENT, IIPSM NIGERIA
- HSE/EIA PROFESSIONAL IIPSM, NIGERIA
- **FUNDAMENTALS OF DIGITAL MARKETING -**GOOGLE DIGITAL SKILLS, NIGERIA

IT Engineer & Instructor, 10/2020 - 05/2021

Fenster Academy - Ogun, Nigeria

- Facilitated trainings, rendered IT support and displayed team leadership, boosting personnel's resource utilisation by 75%.
- Addressed practical matters on special modules whilst offering expert and reliable solutions, manifesting a 90% success rate.
- Maintained equipment in line with HSE practices, recording 0 damage.

Computer Engineering Intern, 01/2016 – 06/2016

Slot Systems Limited - Lagos, Nigeria

- Settled 95% of technical impediments for Windows, MAC-OS and LINUX-based devices within service level agreements.
- Collaborated with the CTO at the National HQ to build and modify computing systems to meet client specifications, boosting customer satisfaction and retention by 40%.
- Resolved complex problems within deadlines, obtaining a 98% customer issue resolution rate.